Guide to the J. Walter Thompson Company. Derek Norman papers, 1965-1993 and undated RL.11608
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company. Derek Norman papers
1965-1993 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company
John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History
Norman, Derek
RL.11608
6.0 Linear Feet
Founded in 1864, the J. Walter Thompson Company (JWT) is one of the oldest and largest enduring advertising agencies in the United States. It is headquartered in New York. Derek Norman was an advertising executive who worked at the JWT London and Chicago offices and later at Leo Burnett agency in Chicago, Ill. Collection includes print advertisements, advertising designs and layouts, storyboards, audio and video cassettes and films of radio and television commercials and other printed materials. British and American companies represented include Chicago Tribune, Commonwealth Edison, John White Footwear, Kellogg, Kodak, Kraft, Lemco stock tablets, Northern Telecom (Nortel) and Oscar Mayer. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Arrangement
Organized into two series: Account Files; Audiovisual Materials.
Biographical / Historical
Founded in 1864, the J. Walter Thompson Company (JWT) is one of the oldest and largest enduring advertising agencies in the United States. It is headquartered in New York. Derek Norman was an advertising executive who worked at the JWT London and Chicago offices and later at Leo Burnett agency in Chicago, Ill.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The J. Walter Thompson Company. Derek Norman papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2014.
Related Materials
Related materials may be found in the following Hartman Center collections:
J. Walter Thompson Company. Account files
J. Walter Thompson Company. Competitive Advertisements
J. Walter Thompson Company. Domestic Advertisements
J. Walter Thompson Company. International Advertisements
Collection Overview
Collection includes print advertisements, advertising designs and layouts, storyboards, audio and video cassettes and films of radio and television commercials and other printed materials. British and American companies represented include Chicago Tribune, Commonwealth Edison, John White Footwear, Kellogg, Kodak, Kraft, Lemco stock tablets, Northern Telecom (Nortel) and Oscar Mayer. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Advertising; Advertising -- Great Britain -- History; Advertising -- United States -- Design; Advertising agencies; Advertising agencies -- Illinois; Advertising agencies -- Great Britain; Advertising agencies -- United States; Advertising executives; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History; Norman, Derek; Kraft Foods Company; Kellogg Company; Eastman Kodak Company; Northern Telecom Inc.; Oscar Mayer & Co
- Account Files, 1965-1992 and undated; 1
  - Chicago Tribune--Advertising designs, undated (Box 1)
  - Chicago Tribune--Advertising designs, undated (Box 2)
  - Chicago Tribune--Print advertisement, undated (Box 3)
  - Commonwealth Edison--Print advertisements, 1991-1992 (Box 3)
  - Commonwealth Edison--Print advertisements, 1991 (Box 5)
  - Commonwealth Edison--Storyboards, undated (Box 5)
  - DiGiorno--Print advertisements, 1991 and undated (Box 2)
  - DiGiorno--Print advertisements, 1991 and undated (Box 3)
  - DiGiorno--Storyboards, 1989-1992; 2 folders (Box 5)
  - John White Footwear (U.K.)--Print advertisements, 1965-1966; 2 folders (Box 4)
  - John White Footwear (U.K.)--Print advertisements, 1965-1966; 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Kellogg--Corn Flakes sketches, undated; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Kellogg--Corn Flakes storyboards, 1995 (Box 1)
  - Kellogg--Corn Flakes storyboards, undated (Box 3)
  - Kellogg--Good Idea storyboards, 1989; 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Kodak (U.K.)--Print advertisements, 1967 and undated; 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Kodak (U.K.)--Print advertisements, 1967 (Box 4)
  - Kodak (U.K.)--Print advertisements, 1967; 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Kraft--Cheese print designs, undated (Box 2)
  - Kraft--Cheez Whiz print advertisements, 1983 (Box 1)
  - Kraft--Cheez Whiz print advertisements, 1983 (Box 3)
  - Kraft--Cracker Barrel print advertisements, 1978 (Box 3)
  - Kraft--Cracker Barrel print advertisements, 1978 (Box 4)
  - Kraft--Philadelphia Cream Cheese, Cracker Barrel print advertisements, 1978-1979 (Box 5)
  - Lemco stock tablets (U.K.)--Print advertisements, circa 1960s (Box 2)
  - Murine--Clear Eyes print advertisement, 1969 (Box 5)
  - Northern Telecom--Booklets, 1981-1982 (Box 1)
  - Northern Telecom--Newspaper insert, 1985 (Box 5)
  - Northern Telecom--Print advertisements, 1986 (Box 2)
  - Northern Telecom--Print advertisements, 1986-1987 (Box 3)
  - Northern Telecom--Print advertisements, 1987 and undated (Box 4)
  - Northern Telecom--Print advertisements, 1986-1987 and undated (Box 6-8)
  - Northern Telecom--Sketches, undated (Box 1)
  - Northern Telecom--Sketches, undated (Box 4)
  - Northern Telecom--Storyboards, undated (Box 3)
  - Oscar Mayer--Print designs, undated (Box 3)
  - Oscar Mayer--Print designs, 1987 (Box 5)
- Audiovisual Materials, 1969-1993 and undated; 2
  - Derek Norman demo reel, 1985 (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11608-Umatic-001)
  - Derek Norman television reel, 1989 (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11608-Umatic-002)
    Scope and Contents
    Includes Kraft, Sears, Beatrice/Aunt Nellie's, Oscar Mayer, Rowntree, Northwest Mutual
  - JWT--Aunt Nellie's Fancy Vegetables, 1984 (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11608-Umatic-003)
    Corn; Snap
  - JWT--Beatrice/Aunt Nellie's, undated (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11608-Umatic-004)
    Peas/Snap; Corn
  - JWT--Kraft/Cableshop, 1982 (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11608-Umatic-005)
    Seafood; Baking; Desserts
  - JWT--Kraft/Casino, 1979 (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11608-Umatic-006)
    Pour Revised; Bucket Revised
  - JWT--Kraft Philadelphia Cream Cheese, 1980 (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11608-Umatic-007)
    "The Cream of Cream Cheese"
  - JWT--Oscar Mayer/Lean Meats, 1987 (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11608-Umatic-008)
    Where; Computer Buff
  - JWT--Oscar Mayer/Bologna, 1987 (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11608-Umatic-009)
    Accountant; Poolside; Piano; Draftsman; Where; Computer Buff
  - JWT--Oscar Mayer/Bologna, 1987 (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11608-Umatic-010)
    Poolside; Piano; Accountant; Draftsman
  - JWT--Oscar Mayer Trademark, undated (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11608-Umatic-011)
    "Little Monsters"
  - JWT--Oscar Mayer, 1987 (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11608-Umatic-012)
    "Up a Tree/Michael"
  - JWT--Sears paint, undated (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11608-Umatic-013)
    "Coveralls" with prices
  - JWT--Sears paint, 1981 (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11608-Umatic-014)
    "Newsreel 1/2 Price" with Ron McAdam voiceover
  - JWT--Sears Better Paint, 1981 (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11608-Umatic-015)
    "Newsreel March Sale"
  - Leo Burnett--Commonwealth Edison, 1993 (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11608-Umatic-016)
    Sorting Clothes; Light Bulb; Oven Peeping; Ice Cream Test; Dollar Bill Test
  - Leo Burnett--Kellogg Corn Flakes, 1993 (Box AV2, Video-cassette RL11608-Umatic-017)
    Baseball Poster Promo; Team Helmet Promo
  - Leo Burnett--Kraft/DiGiorno, 1992 (Box AV2, Video-cassette RL11608-Umatic-018)
    "Awning Animatic"
  - Handgun control PSA radio, undated (Box AV2, Audio-cassette RL11608-CS-001)
  - Mark Russell "Exports", undated (Box AV2, Audio-cassette RL11608-CS-002)
  - Northern Telecom IOS radio, undated (Box AV2, Audio-cassette RL11608-CS-003)
    Tuesday; Closet
  - Northern Telecom DSS radio Mark Russell spots, 1988 (Box AV2, Audio-cassette RL11608-CS-004)
  - Northern Telecom, undated (Box AV2, Audio-cassette RL11608-CS-005)
    "Railroads"
  - Handgun control PSA radio, undated (Box AV2, Audio-reel RL11608-RR-001)
    Preacher; Rage to Live; Say No to Handguns; Don't Hand Me; Bleeding Hearts; Every Hour; Russian Roulette; Contributions; Nothing Is Done
  - Northern Telecom radio with Mark Russell, undated (Box AV2, Audio-reel RL11608-RR-002)
  - Northern Telecom, 1983 (Box AV2, Audio-reel RL11608-RR-003)
    Rivers; Railroads demo composites
  - Northern Telecom, 1983 (Box AV2, Audio-reel RL11608-RR-004)
    Rivers; Railroads alternate music mixes
  - Orchestrated Office, undated (Box AV2, Audio-reel RL11608-RR-005)
  - JWT--Seven-Up radio, 1969 (Box AV2, Audio-reel RL11608-RR-006)
    Cola Hearted Woman; Underground; Corey
  - Experimental TV: Seven-Up and RCA, 1970 (Box AV2, Film-reel RL11608-F16-001)
  - JWT London--John White Cosmetics, 1967 (Box AV2, Film-reel RL11608-F16-002)
  - Jovan, undated (Box AV2, Film-reel RL11608-F16-003)
  - JWT office tour at John Hancock Center 5:08 transfer from film, undated (Box AV2, Film-reel RL11608-F16-004)
  - JWT--Kraft/Casino, undated (Box AV2, Film-reel RL11608-F16-005)
    "Buckets"
  - JWT--Kraft, undated (Box AV2, Film-reel RL11608-F16-006)
    "Ready When You Are New"
  - JWT--Sears paint, undated (Box AV2, Film-reel RL11608-F16-007)
    "Coveralls June"
  - JWT--Sedelmeier, undated (Box AV2, Film-reel RL11608-F16-008)
  - JWT--Seven-Up radio, undated (Box AV2, Film-reel RL11608-F16-009)
  - JWT--Seven-Up radio, 1969-1970 (Box AV2, Film-reel RL11608-F16-010)
    Radio; Turn On, Turn Un; Uncola Float; Get Un With It; Half An Un
  - Untitled, undated (Box AV2, Film-reel RL11608-F16-011)
  - Untitled, undated (Box AV2, Film-reel RL11608-F16-012)
  - Miscellaneous elements from JWT London, undated (Box AV2, Film-reel RL11608-F35-001)
    Includes Persil (Tony Scott spot), Coleman Mustard
  - JWT office tour at John Hancock Center 5:08 transfer from film, undated (Box AV2, Video-disc RL11608-OP-001)